Hello everyone. Good morning.
I want to say for all those people sort of standing in the back, you know,
if it's not a standing ovation, you're you're welcome.
There are a lot of, like, middle seats or like seats across the board.
So feel free to come in.
I won't be afraid if you sort of shuffle, shuffle
through and find a seat to listen with more comfort.
I am guy or guy.
I'm the CEO and founder here at Tessl, with Simon Maple,
and I'm excited for two days of sharing and learning.
And I do love the hallway track.
I love the talks on it, but I just love the conversations and the learnings.
And I'd love for you to to share some of those learnings.
You're here to to collaborate, not just to talk.
And indeed,
I want to talk to you about sort of why skills, I believe, are the new code.
So we
founded Tessl two plus years ago, and we we did it out of the belief
that software development is transforming from revolving around code
and instructions to revolving around intent.
Sorry. Let me try that again.
Revolving around code
and implementation to revolving around intent and instructions.
And I think that's far
less controversial today, two years ago, we believe that there's a new dev paradigm
to be had around it, but we didn't know quite what it would look like.
And I think today we're starting to see that sort of new development
stack come into view, which I find quite exciting.
And so we're seeing the kind of a bit of a layered software stack.
At the bottom are the new primitives, the models that roll building on.
Clearly, they are the new superpower
that we've received and we're trying to build for those
on top of those are tools, which I'll talk about some more,
which helped turn models into agents, giving them arms and legs to be able
to affect the world and gather information.
There's context that guides those models of it.
And then increasingly, there is a harness that constrains the model
or packages a lot of things together.
I'll talk about these three layers in more depth in a section,
and then harnesses compose into factory lines that combine them
all and create these pipelines and into full on factories.
So I want to talk a little bit
about that stack, and I'll come back to this view later on.
Let's start by talking about tools.
So tools are probably the easiest to understand.
These are pieces of software that are utilities that in part indeed
they turn models into agents.
And so they they enable a model to interact with the world affected,
gather context, etc.
but they're also oftentimes means to do a thing
more cheaply or faster or better than just passing it on to the model.
It's not always raw intelligence that you want for every problem.
There are a variety of types of tools, but the most common ones are command
line interface like CLI tools, MCP tools that get interacted
with directly from the agent, and then APIs or network related invoked.
And all of those are our means to be able to perform action.
For instance, grep allows an agent to find information in many,
many files efficiently and without needing to load up all those tokens.
So a little bit more cheaply.
Or if you think about like FFmpeg is a video editor and it can edit videos
in a far less error prone way than a model will do, and again cheaply and faster.
And tools, as are software,
and they compose so we know we can pipe them into one another.
We can write code that composes them together.
And so we don't just have generic utilities, we can create
custom tools that are fitting our purpose at a given time.
So they're very powerful and we're familiar with them.
The next layer
is new to the AI world and it is that of context.
Now everything is context in LLMs, right?
Eventually you're kind of managing what goes into that LLM call.
However, when we think about context files that we are developing,
they end up focusing on information that the agent either doesn't have
and can't know or information that it can figure out,
but it's very inefficient or error prone for it to find out.
And we find that it kind of boils down into these three types of things.
There's policies and practices, right?
We got in a room and we agreed this is how we will use this framework.
This is our security policy.
This is our API design. Right.
Capture those and inform the agent around that.
The second is specs.
Specs to me are definitions of product.
So it's information about the product you are building to inform the agent.
Better to say when you're building things, know that this exists or products
you are using, especially when those are APIs or things that move quickly.
So again,
maybe the agent can trial and error it, but it's expensive and won't work well.
And the third bucket is workflows.
It's like this is how you will do incident response right.
This is how you will review code
sometimes to help the agents succeed,
because the agents are just not good enough yet doing it on its own.
And sometimes it's because you want it consistently.
Like I don't care that you can troubleshoot this incident on your own.
I want it done in a repeatable fashion so everybody can relate to it.
The other matrix around context is how you load it.
And so over there
you've got it's a bit more technical, but you've got rules
that always get shoved into the context window, right.
Your cloud MD or your agents and D file or gets put there.
Clearly you need to be mindful of its size.
You've got skills that are more loaded on demand, either
because the user invoked them or through some hints to the agent,
and then you have passive context, just docs like architecture
and D or other information that's just available there in the repo.
Hopefully the agent can find it with a generic search and the likes.
And I'm going to
refer to context as skills mostly for the rest of the presentation,
just for simplicity of it.
But there are some sort of subtleties around it.
And importantly, skills compose as well, and we don't think about it as much.
It's not as obvious
as tools, but they do gather up first of all, skills called tools.
And that's, I think, fairly common.
In fact, many skills exist to be able to talk about how to how to use tools.
But skills can call other skills
you can have, for instance, an incident response workflow that calls one skill
to collect the logs that uses the Datadog or other tools, then another one to do
road course analysis, another one to log the things in a linear or a JIRA.
And so you can compose those.
And that's amazing because composability is what makes software powerful, right?
We can build on one another.
Imagine every time you wanted to write a web
page, you'd have to write a kernel like that doesn't work well.
We want to be able to build on one each other's work.
So. So we
have tools and we have skills and a slightly newer entrant in terms
of thinking about them as developers is this world of harnesses.
Now, harness is deterministic software that wraps a probabilistic model.
It harnesses the model.
For instance, cloud code is a harness,
and it controls a bunch of things about how to interact with the model.
It knows how to load the rules from cloud and how to load the skills.
It has a config file that defines things that it would apply
in the container to constrain the model to, to limit, to say what does it have?
It defines which tools are available and you can customize that model.
Increasingly, these harnesses are becoming kind of frameworks that are extensible.
So you can create plugins into these agents that have your tools
or your skills, and they also allow you to create hooks,
which again, are these deterministic pieces of software.
Every time a prompt comes along, run this hook
and I might edit that prompt, I might disallow it and block it right.
Every time you call a tool, I might do that.
And so these are deterministic functionality, pieces of functionality
that again are potentially cheaper, potentially faster, potentially better,
and definitely more deterministic than just calling the model.
So this interaction is important.
And of course there are many types of different harnesses.
There's the popular ones over here.
And increasingly it's become much easier to build your own harness.
And people do that as well. So harnesses are important.
They help the model and they constrain the model in a deterministic fashion.
And it harnesses are becoming a core component of how to make a
development scale.
And you see this from a bunch of thought leaders. Just a couple of examples.
Here are intercom talked about how they, for instance, block GitHub
pull request creation unless the relevant skill was loaded.
So they literally block the action.
If the skill was not loaded,
the agent knew that the skill was there, so why wouldn't it load it?
Well, this commandeers control from the from the model.
It says the model doesn't get to choose.
This will always be loaded.
So it gives you some of those controls.
And OpenAI with Ryan is actually going to be speaking later on.
And great talk that you definitely need to talk about.
This is like an earlier post from him, talked about a much more custom harness
that they've built that does a variety of things,
including a common practice of not allowing a commit
unless a certain test coverage has been included.
So again, all of those are examples of deterministic software that wraps
the probabilistic model and allows us to create control so we can
make things repeatable.
And unsurprisingly, harnesses compose as well.
So you can take, say, a product harness that is very good at elaborating
on a feature request and a coding harness that knows how to build a thing,
and a security harness that has to secure it, and maybe a DevOps harness
that knows how to deploy it and package the normal all up into this system.
Harness that I call a factory line that looks like a pipeline.
You might get a type of input in in this example, a feature request,
and you might have a shipped feature on the other side.
And so harness is composed, which again is great because this is the way
that we can scale them.
So coming back to the stack this starts looking like a software stack, right?
It starts looking like these are layers that we are developing.
Each of these layers composes the layer below it.
And so tools call the models and context guides the tools that call the models
and feed the models directly and harnesses package up a bunch of these things.
Now all of these terms are working progress harness is probably
the most abused at the moment, and I'm sure there will change over time.
But still, it's something we can start reasoning about.
And I think it's interesting to see that amidst that layer,
the tools, the harnesses, the factory lines, the factories,
they're all actually software, their software that wraps a model.
But really the two kind of new compute entities over here
are the models themselves and the context that is native to the models.
It literally goes into the matrices and modifies what is being done.
And so my view on this is that really the
a lot of this is frameworks, but context is the new code.
It is the place in which you program the model.
And you do this sometimes locally and sometimes reusable.
So when we think about context again, everything is context.
But when you talk about the context you provide as humans,
we provide as developers, it ranges from things that are more in time,
just in time like prompts to be able to say guide,
like literally in an interactive session to docs
and some information we store alongside our code
that is probably project specific rules that are sometimes project specific
and sometimes get reused across projects and into skills.
And skills are really designed to be reusable.
They're like libraries. They are.
If you're only doing one thing, something once,
you're not going to create a skill for it, you're just going to prompt for it.
If you think you're going to do it more times, you turn it into a skill.
So it's designed to be reusable.
So reusability is great.
It's a means of scaling.
And so we're seeing skills explode.
And there are many stats on it on the public ecosystem.
I've actually just completed an analysis from GitHub on it
that shows there are about 2 million skills on GitHub.
This is up from about zero at the beginning of the year.
So it's a it's many, many, many, many skills across many repos.
And some of these are open close
and some are high quality some low quality of course.
But it's a lot.
And on the other side, I don't have numbers for this,
but what we're seeing is an explosion of skills within the enterprise.
And again, going kind of in a similar ramp, which is amazing but also daunting.
And to talk a bit about how it feels.
I want to give the sort of real world testimonial around this.
Oh, oh.
So I think
John Travolta was ahead of his time over here, and
I think his has explained it very succinctly.
This is how most enterprises feel.
They've got skills, they're multiplying and they're losing control.
They don't know how to handle that.
And so moving on.
Let's talk a little bit about some of these challenges
that we see with with skills and with context.
The first challenge unfortunately is security.
So skills are actually executed by the agent.
And they may or may not be nefarious.
And so we're seeing a variety of risky skills come along.
We're seeing malicious skills
that are literally built to to cause harm in the open claw ecosystem.
We've seen over 30% of skills to be malicious on it.
It's a very easy way to hack in.
We're seeing what we call negligence skills.
So skills that really urge the user to do something but
do not have any safety instructions in it, do not set any boundaries.
So make sure you update the table correctly and there should be a line there
like do not drop the table as famously happened in a few places.
And so some of these safety instructions are lacking.
And there could be vulnerable skills that guide for information that just
sort of leaves you expose.
The most common example of that is to use API tokens or other secrets
as part of something that is visible in the logs, and might be available
if it's available to the agent, it might be manipulated out.
So security is a concern.
And if security is a concern, governance becomes a concern.
Because if some risks are some skills are risky
then you have to ask well like which skills.
Am I even using and do I know if they're risky and who's using which skill?
And if one of them was malicious or was compromised,
would I know that that happened?
How do I track the track record?
And so especially for organizations that are sort of mid-size and up,
and really it should be for everyone
some element of governance of just like know what's going on, some supply chain
hygiene comes along and you have to do that.
So security and governance is kind of one bucket.
The next bucket of concern is around reuse and collaboration.
And I love this story from the developer in sort of a large unicorn that has over
1000 developers told me, which was just very exemplary of how things happened.
So they had everybody loved skills and everybody was building their own skill.
And a lot of people did the same skill again and again,
whether it's related to the app or a code review or a test creation or something,
many of us have the same ideas.
And so they say, well, that's wasteful.
Let's, let's create a shared repository.
So they created a shared repository and everybody uploaded those skills
or started uploading those skills in there.
And very quickly it became a mess.
And what happened was one, all these duplicates just went into the repo.
But any new developer coming along and saying, oh,
I don't want to write my own code review skill, I'll use one of those.
There are seven over here. Which one should I choose?
Like there's no indication of which one is good.
They've seen a works on my machine problem, right?
Where one developer is using one agent uploads a skill and it turns out
that skill doesn't actually work well on another agent or collaboration.
Problems with these PR that don't go anywhere because one person
wrote a skill, another helpfully came and proposed the modification.
How is the skill owner know whether this change is making it better or worse?
Like there's no tools around it.
And so nobody trusted anything in the repo.
And eventually everybody came back to writing their own.
So not very effective on it.
And I think we'll come back to this, but I think big evidence kind of gap
here is there was no quality control and indication of what is of good quality,
and there was no management of the dependencies.
And so
security and governance, reuse and collaboration.
And then the third bucket is really life cycle.
And I think we've come to appreciate and know that software rots, right.
If you write
a piece of excellent software today and you do not maintain it, over time,
it will stop working and eventually it will be harmful in your system.
I think we've had enough mileage to know that the same is true for skills.
You can create a skill.
It works very well today and you don't touch it.
And then over time the model's changed.
The APIs around it change and might it might be incorrect.
The infrastructure it's deployed and will change. Many things will change.
I wrote three months here in the AI world it might be two weeks
and your skill is already outdated and it rots and it becomes less effective
and eventually harmful, actually guiding the agent to do the wrong thing.
So we have to think about how do we maintain skills.
Nobody likes maintenance, but we have to think about it.
It is like a piece of software,
and there's a bit of a carrot
and stick going on over here, because maintenance is the stick.
If you do not maintain, it's going to rot, it's going to cause damage.
But now with agents, if you do maintain, you can actually turn maintenance
into optimization.
You can observe agent logs and pull requests and production logs
and other information about what is actually happened,
and automatically turn that into improvements
and track that along into new skills, into modified skills, into removed skills.
Always go to delete code, right.
Just try to observe that.
And so that's the carrot an opportunity and a risk.
And both of them boil down to high quality autonomous agent powered maintenance.
And so these are the three common change errors.
There are like challenge areas that people are are feeling.
And we're hearing it.
It's actually amazingly consistent as we talk to different organizations
about how they're adopting skills and agent dev.
And the good news
is they sound awfully familiar.
All of those are problems that we have seen and addressed,
and we've built amazing tools on how to deal with them
in code, in software development.
And so really what we need to do is we need to change our view around skills
and not just think of them as like words that we move around.
They're not like your your intranet docs, your sort of notion or confluence docs.
They are like pieces of software.
And I want to talk about five core kind of quality and software
development tools that we need are on static analysis, dynamic
tests, security tools, dependency management and observability.
And talk about how can we apply those to skills,
because I think those are the solutions for many problems.
So let's start from static analysis.
Static analysis
is the exercise of inspecting code without actually running it.
Right. And we've seen it evolve in depth.
You can have simple enters that.
Simply check if you're sort of styling is a certain path right.
Or some typing things in non typed languages you can go into deep
security analysis analyzers that inspect data flows within your
your application and your code and find some deep problems.
And today you have a generic reviews
that can even look into the substance of what is the application doing.
In all of those cases, it doesn't run the code, it just looks at it.
And so it's an easy way to scale it.
And typically one kind of measuring stick for all of your applications.
So you will review the same way many many different types of changes.
So this is directly applicable to skills.
We can use things like linting Tessl has one version of that
which is linked to just look to see.
Does the skill have the right fields. Does it have the right forms.
You can look at quality measures or security measures
to be able to repeatedly find best practice flaws.
Tessl.
We use Tessl review to match a skill against the anthropic best practices.
Does it have proper progressive disclosure?
Does it have is it concise enough?
Is it declare the activation well enough?
And then of course we have the security analysis.
We'll talk about that in a second.
And then you can get into custom a generic review that actually looks
at the substance of it, which is pretty much the same as the other ones.
Again, at Tessl, we do that through the review.
So static analysis is hopefully straightforward.
And there's really no reason why we wouldn't do that. It is.
It's just about the definition of of of stopping and defining what
good looks like, what is correct functionality.
The second world is tests and we all love tests.
And you know, I think again with mileage a little bit,
there are probably enough gray beards in the
in the room that we will have experienced how it feels amazing
to just ship something and not worry about tests,
and then it feels not so amazing the day after as you try to modify it.
And we've kind of come to learn, you know, in
like visceral learnings, why we need tests to be able to scale.
And you don't write tests for everything, but you have to have some tests.
Otherwise you can't build upon what you've done.
You can't develop.
And because tests are test is a very big world.
But all of tests, all the tests run some piece of your software
and they scale from unit tests that are cheap and easy to run.
So we run them in our CI
and we build them out for a unit of software into integration tests
that get a little bit into dependency world.
And what happens for this piece of software?
Not in isolation, but with a bunch of others.
It's a bit more expensive to run, it's a bit harder to maintain and write,
but it's useful all the way to end to end tests that are expensive.
And they need a production like system and you run them, but they're very valuable.
So we we invest in them proportionally
in skills.
The equivalent is evals.
You take, you define an environment for some skill to run.
You actually practically run an agent
through the through a task in that environment.
And then you judge the result.
And you can do all of those in a variety of ways, just like tests, but
you actually invoke it and you can do it in varying levels of depth.
And I think what we're seeing is we're seeing at the bottom layer,
we're seeing skill evals.
Skill is a unit of software.
So like unit tests, you're testing the skill in isolation.
It's like a library that you're testing.
Define what correct looks like.
Build from there. Run an evaluation.
You can do that
only for the agents that you care about, or even with cheap open models,
just to know that you're not regressing, just to know that
however it is that worked before it still working.
Now you can go into project evals
that test a project, say a repo in with multiple skills, right?
I have 20 skills installed.
This is a more similarly
like a better simulation of production of like a closer to reality world.
And maybe I can take an old pull request and I can convert or extract a scenario
out of that and load that
with my sort of 20 skills and see again whether the judgment is,
does it get a high score, right, what is the correct output of it.
And so those are great to optimize project context, help you delete things
and help you know whether it's useful or harmful to add a skill to your project.
And then you can have more comprehensive test you can actually use
in any of these evals to be able to run model evaluations on it.
But if you really want a
comprehensive test to be able to say, well, in my organization, in my develop,
can I use GLM 5 or 2 six, which is much cheaper than opus?
Or do I need to move to opus 48?
Or maybe I continuously failed in this task and this new fancy model came along.
Does it help me get past that?
Then you create something
that is more simulated, more extensive, like the end to end test.
And these are not perfect analogies, but we can think about evals as tests
and we can write them incrementally,
but we have to get into the habit of writing them.
And it's worth noting that just like tests scenario quality matters,
we you can write tests that make you feel good
because you get the coverage and they give you very little quality
barometers like, I got the 100%, but, you know, it doesn't actually find bugs.
And you can write a few tests that are super, super valuable.
And you know that you can trust that framework.
So you can change and you can run faster with more confidence.
Same is true for scenarios.
You can write some scenarios that are amazing
quality parameters, and you can write some that are just a waste of time in tokens.
So you have to think about that.
Now I will say
we're big believers in in in Tessl.
Hopefully we've heard us ramble about this for for quite a while,
and we have kind of good, good capabilities around it.
We help you generate the test with scenario scenario,
and we help you run them with the Tessl eval.
And then one sort of side benefits, which we haven't really done
well in software, is once you do static and dynamic analysis,
you can actually aggregate a bit of this view and create a quality score
so that when you're consuming a skill, like in that shared repo,
you can actually figure out which one is is of high quality or not.
And quality scores are always going to be imperfect,
but they are useful.
There are means of still knowing directionally this one is better than the other.
So the third bucket is security testing.
And it's actually very directly applicable to what we do in software.
We can do static analysis. We should do static analysis.
I was very happy to see all the apps players introduce
skill scanning, sneak being one of them, but many of the others did as well.
And I think that's exciting.
You know, having found that sneak in, I'm clearly passionate about security
and embedding it into software development on it.
I think this is directly applicable.
It says specifically we integrated
sneak into our registry and we will support others to try those out.
There is a more nascent world
of dynamic tests, so this is more like red teaming and testing your skill.
It's tricky because these skills are very varied in functionality,
so it's hard to identify what is a correct anticipated behavior and what is not.
But it's an evolving world.
And then you need supply chain security.
So you need to know we've all now experienced LLM and a variety
of other supply chain attacks that have been coming fast and furious.
The same is happening or will happen for skills.
So you have to be able to track what you're using,
which gets us into the fun world of dependencies.
And another famous quote from
John Travolta is the dependencies are fun.
Like, well, even even he didn't say that.
That is not the case.
In fact, no one ever said dependency management
is fun, dependency management is a pain and dependencies are a pain.
They might upgrade your application when you break your application.
When you upgrade, they conflict with one another.
If there's stale, you might not be able to use some new system of it.
If they're brand new, they might be compromised.
You know, Joy.
And there's a reason we invested in package managers
like those exist for a reason.
They're widely used for a reason because these are real problems.
So again, if we think about skills as the new code,
it becomes fairly evident that we need dependency management for skills.
And Tessl offers one of those on it.
There's a few nascent open source ones.
If you have proper dependency management you can use them.
Use the registries to be able to discover skills.
You can have version management.
So when a problem occurs, you know which version it occurred in.
And you can roll out a fix to the new version and see if it fixed it.
You when you install like say we test will install
you install a skill or we package them up in plugins.
Lo and behold it remembers what you installed so you can run a Tessl
and it will update those versions.
And that gives you some supply chain visibility.
And then once you have all of those, you can start introducing things
like quality and security controls
to be able to
set a bar for what gets installed or what gets published into your workspace.
And then you can introduce some cross agent compatibility.
So you, just like NPM, doesn't care if you're on a windows or a Linux machine.
It's just obvious that for you, can we do the same as we do for agents?
And then the last
bit I'm going to talk about is observability.
And at the end of the day, we can build really quality software.
But there's only so far you can get in the lab.
And so you can build your software, you can test it, you can secure it,
you can optimize it. And then at some point you need to step out.
And that comes into observability. For agents.
Runtime observability is monitoring the coding agents.
And when you monitor
those you can use those to improve the quality of what you have.
So you can extract real world eval scenarios and problems
and use those to update and optimize your skills.
And you can mine for gaps.
So you can look at agents success as a whole and
extract out of
that opportunities for new skills or things that you should remove.
And in general, as you think about this whole process, combining
all these tools together, you increasingly should see a development lifecycle.
But it should be a context development lifecycle, not a skill,
not a software development lifecycle.
We should, as humans, live in the context development lifecycle and leave the SDLC
to the agents or engage be able to enable the agents to do the SDLC
in which we generate context, evaluate and test it,
optimize it as we need to distribute it via good package management.
Securely consume them, observe what has happened, and do that again and again.
So in summary,
we have a new software stack we for agent development.
It builds on the models that are like our operating systems.
We need to make sure what we build is compatible with them.
We have tools as utilities.
We have context as a new code.
We have harnesses that are like frameworks.
Not every developer will
build their own harness, but probably more and more organizations would
substantially customize harnesses if not build their own in those
those composing to factory lines that feel very much like pipelines.
You have repeatable type of input coming in, successful
output coming out and into whole dev processes in factories.
And within those skills are the new code,
and we should treat them that way and give them the right tools for it.
Again, hopefully a test will help you do a bunch of those.
I'd encourage you to try them out,
but just the mental model is even more important than that.
And then one last thing before I wrap, we at Tessl.
We're excited about this, and we've been giving
building tools to be able to do agentic development and develop skills.
And we've been giving you skills to do that.
And we think we should give you a harness as well.
And so we have a nascent version of the Tessl agent, which is a vertical agent
to help you develop context harnesses, factory lines, factories and more.
You can use that locally. As you build those things.
You can use it in the pipeline
as you continuously optimize them, or even from the Tessl Control Center.
So it's really new if you want early access
and you want to be part of this and can spend a bit of time
trying it out and giving us feedback, stop by the booth for us.
Or if you're on the on the stream here, you can check out Tessl's agent eval to
sign up for early access.
So that's it for me.
What I want to close off is just to say a huge thank you.
As we get into this conference,
we we believe, indeed, that there's a new software development paradigm
that is coming into view, and we're excited that we're building it together.
We think building a new dev paradigm is not a vendor or sort of any company's job.
It is a community activity.
So, as Simon pointed out, I'd encourage you to engage here, learn,
but also share your learnings.
That's a big part of what we're doing here.
So looking forward for two amazing days and just want to say a huge
thank you.
Thanks, guys!